(忆往昔)
我没想到萨姆会回来
I didn't expect Sam to come back.
但在他走进这个门的那一刻  我就知道了
But the minute he walked through that door, I knew.
一切都结束了
It was over.
我有点儿不对劲  我需要帮助
There's something wrong with me. I need help.
他的灵魂
It's his soul.
-不见了  -那会在哪儿
- It's gone. - So, where is it?
应该还在封印米迦勒和路西法的牢笼里
Still in the cage with Michael and Lucifer.
-那就把它弄回来啊  -那不可能
- Well, then, just get it back. - That's not possible.
你已经丧失了本性
You've got no instinct.
你可真是有大麻烦了
I mean, you are seriously messed up.
我不清楚你是什么  反正不是萨姆
I don't know what you are 'cause you're not Sam.
迪恩  够了
Dean, come on.
别装蒜了
Stop pretending.
-你说得没错  -哪方面
- You were right. - About?
我确实不是你弟弟
I'm not your brother.
我压根就不是真的在乎你
Like I don't even really care about you.
或是我是该觉得内疚
And maybe I should feel guilty.
但我没有
But I don't.
(如今)
(埃尔伍德  印第安纳州)
你看到没
Did you see that?
看到什么
See what?
有东西在那儿
There's something out there.
帕特里克
Patrick!
有东西在玉米地里
Something out in the corn.
帕特里克  你吓着我了
Patrick, you're freaking me out.
我就去看一眼
I'm just having a quick look.
帕特里克
Patrick!
Patrick.
帕特里克
Patrick!
[邪恶力量 第6季第9集]
(禁止进入  地区演习指挥部命令  2014年8月1日  堪萨斯城  命令号:84834343QE)
(警告!危险!  请勿入内  剧毒物质)
我要说  我相信印第安纳州的埃尔伍德
I'm here because I believe that Elwood, Indiana,
已然成为了外星人的活动集中地
has become a center of extraterrestrial activity.
当时一道光闪过  接着帕特里克就消失了
There was this light, and then Patrick just vanished.
一切都成真了
It's all happening, you know?
这些实体会帮助人类进入到新的阶段
I mean, these entities have come to help push humanity to the next stage.
我是小韦恩·惠特克
My name is Wayne Whitaker, Jr.,
我自己录下了许多的目击实录
and I have personally recorded dozens of eyewitness accounts
其中都提到了天空中的奇怪光束
strange lights in the sky,
不明生物试图与目击者交流
mysterious presences attempting contact.
自从这事儿闹的满城风雨之后
Since this whole damn circus has blown into town,
就没人关心有四个人失踪了  束手无策
no one seems to realize we've got four missing-persons cases, wide open.
我的朋友们失去了至亲
My friends lost loved ones.
到底怎么了  有东西抓走了他
What happened to him? Something took him.
我知道的
I know it!
按我们圈内人的说法  我们卷入了"飞碟门"
We are right in the middle of what we in the field like to call a "U.F.O. Flap,"
此刻的我无比激动
And I am as happy as a pig in shoes.
我可以保证这绝对不是飞碟作怪
I can guarantee you this has nothing to do with U.F.O.S
跟什么外星人之类的半毛钱关系都没有
or little green men or anything extraterrestrial whatsoever.
那当然不是什么飞碟啦
Of course it's not U.F.O.S.
是精灵才对
It's fairies.
精灵
Fairies?
好的  谢谢您的高见
Okay, well, thank you for your input.
怎么  光是飞碟您觉得还不够疯狂么
What, flying saucers not insane enough for you?
你是哪家报社的来着
What newspaper did you say you work for?
你要是想添油加醋自嗨一下
Look, if you want to add glitter to that glue you're sniffing,
随便你  但是别跟我们这儿发疯
That's fine, but don't dump your wackadoo all over us.
-我们可不想掺和进来  -好了  我们问完了
- We'd rather not step in it. - Okay, we -- we -- we're done.
你丢的不过就是一些小猫  大姐
The only thing you're missing is a couple dozen cats, sister.
是的  他血糖高容易激动
Yeah. It's -- it's a blood-sugar thing. Oh.
抱歉了
My apologies.
-干嘛  -干嘛  你还敢问
- What? - "What?"  You gotta ask?
对啊  没错  你确实得问
Right, yes. You do have to ask.
我很抱歉  但这简直就是搞笑呢
Look, I'm sorry, but this is all a big joke, right?
我们不会真要查什么飞碟吧  太扯了
I mean, we're not actually taking this U.F.O. crap seriously?
当然  外星人那些都是假的  地球人都知道
No, man. E.T. is made of rubber. Everybody knows that.
但那4个人确确实实是失踪了
But there are four legitimate vanishings in this town.
一定有古怪
Something's going on.
还有  萨姆  顺便说一下
And, Sam, by the way,
被谣言所骗又不是那位女士的错
it's not the lady's fault she took the brown acid.
没错  那又怎样
Yeah. So?
共情  老弟  共情
Empathy, man. Empathy.
以前的萨姆会用泪汪汪的狗狗眼看她
I mean, the old Sam would've given her some-some wussified, dew-eyed crap.
因为以前的萨姆有灵魂
Old Sam had a soul.
有人性  随便吧
Was a soul. Whatever.
是的  没错  但你现在没有灵魂
Right. Yes. And -- and -- and -- but you don't.
或是没人性  随便吧
Or aren't. Whatever.
-好吧  -行吧
- Right. - Right.
-你都不在乎  -那
- You don't care. - Well...
你必须得在乎
You have to care!
究竟该在乎什么
About what, exactly?
周遭的一切  伙计
About everything, man!
至少  你得有点人性吧
A-about being human, at least!
迪恩  你显然是相当在乎  那很好
Look, Dean, you obviously care. A lot. And that's great.
但  但我不在乎的事
But -- but I can't care about what --
我就是不在乎  懂吗
what I can't care about, you know?
你要我怎么办呢  假装吗
What do you want me to do, fake it?
是的  就是那样  假装一下
Yes. Absolutely. Fake it.
假装到你真得在乎为止
Fake it till you make it.
你不是要我事事坦诚的吗
What happened to you wanting me to be all honest?
你想成为真人的话  皮诺曹
Hey, you want to be a real boy, pinocchio,
就必须得有点儿人样
You got to act the part.
我以前就在假装  迪恩
I was faking it, Dean!
从咱俩重新一起猎魔开始
Ever since we got back on the road together,
我说句话都得斟酌半天
I-I was picking every frickin' word!
-累死我了  -好了  好了
- It's exhausting! - Okay, all right.
在找回你的灵魂之前
But until we get you back on the soul train,
我来当你的良心  行了吗
I'll be your conscience, okay?
也是说你是我的  杰米尼·克力克特
So you're saying you'll be my...Jiminy Cricket.
给我闭嘴
Shut up.
不过  没错  你个该死的木偶人
But, yeah, you freakin' puppet.
我就是这意思
That's exactly what I'm saying.
布伦南先生
Mr. Brennan?
我们是《镜报》的
We're with the Mirror.
-我们是想来问问你  -问什么
- We'd just like to ask you -- what?
想问帕特里克的事吗
Is this about Patrick?
帕特里克已经走了
Patrick's gone.
失踪了  没错  是的
Missing. Right, yes.
我们就是想跟你谈这事儿
That's -- that's what we want to talk to you about.
你儿子是第一个失踪的人
Now, your son was the first to disappear.
第一个被带走的
First to be taken.
被带走
Taken?
滚出去
Get out.
滚
Out!
布伦南先生  你觉得谁把你儿子带走的
Mr. Brennan, who do you believe took your son?
你们帮不了我的
You people can't help me.
我儿子永远都回不来了
My boy is never coming back.
听上去你似乎很肯定
You sound awfully sure.
什么意思
Excuse me?
似乎你明明知道却故意隐瞒着什么
Like you know something you're not talking about.
行了  够了
Okay, all right.
你知道他们怎么说
You know what they say --
72小时
72 hours.
时间一过  找回失踪之人的几率就几乎为零
After that, the odds of finding a missing person drop to nothing, right?
但是  事事总有不同
Well, every case is different.
已经好几周了
It's been weeks.
好吧
Right.
听着
Listen, uh...
要是你想到什么
Call us...
给我们打电话
if anything comes to mind.
好的
Okay.
这样可以吗
Is that all right?
你怎么想
What do you think?
我觉得他有所隐瞒
I think he's hiding something.
你留下来看着这个钟表匠
Why don't you stay and watch watchmaker,
看看夜幕降临之后他会不会有所行动
see what happens when the sun goes down.
-我去看看那片麦田怪圈  -好滴
- I'll go check out the crop circles. - Okeydokey.
但是不许以任何形式
But do not engage with, maim,
伤害或者杀害布伦南
or in any way kill Brennan.
事实上  所有事你都不许自己擅自做决定
In fact, I don't want you making any judgment calls whatsoever.
有情况  就打给我
Anything happens, call me.
别忘了  杰米尼  我一整年都是自己猎魔的
You know, Jiminy, I was on my own for a whole year.
没有你  我也做得挺好
I did fine without you.
没错
Yeah.
但你定义的"好"  我不敢恭维
I don't want to know your definition of "Fine."
什么
What?
他唯一的行动就是各种酗酒
Only thing this guy's up to is alcoholism.
很好
Good.
我想我应该再去找他谈谈
You know, maybe I should go talk to him again.
不是你说他对我们有所隐瞒的吗
I mean, you're the one who said he's hiding something.
嘘
Shh, shh, shh!
怎么了  你看见什么了吗
What? You see something?
迪恩  发生什么了
Dean, what's up?
等等
Hang on a second.
天哪
Holy...
-飞碟  有飞碟  -哥们  别叫了
- U.F.O.! U.F.O.!   - Whoa. Dude, stop yelling.
信号不好
You're breaking up.
最后一句我没听清楚
I didn't catch that last part.
接触  接触啦
Close encounter! Close encounter!
接触
Close encounter?
哪一类的  第一还是第二
What kind? First, second?
他们正在追我
They're after me!
已经是第三类了啊  你最好快点跑  兄弟
Third kind already? You better run, man.
第四类好像就是爆菊了
I think the fourth kind is a butt thing.
共情啊  萨姆  共情
Empathy, Sam! Empathy!
他们还追着你吗
They still after you?
来吧
Come on!
迪恩  你还在吗
Dean? Are you there?
怎么了
What happened?
迪恩
Dean?
谢谢
Thanks.
所以说  真的是有飞碟咯
So, they're real. U.F.O.S.
就像我之前说过的  孩子
Like I said before, son --
真相就在眼前
The truth is out there.
好吧  你是专家
Okay. You're the expert.
我怎么才能抓到它们
How do I get 'em?
再说一遍
Come again?
你捕获外星人  不是吗
Well, you hunt E.T.S, right?
我要知道怎么才能捉住它们
I need to know how to get them.
咱俩同病相怜了
Uh, you and me both.
就这些
This is it?
要我说  三十年的目击实录足以说明问题了
Well, I'd say that 30 years of eyewitness accounts
这些是难以争辩的铁证
speak for themselves, as incontrovertible proof.
对  好吧
Yeah, right.
我哥哥被绑架了
My brother was abducted,
对于证据什么的我毫不怀疑
so I'm pretty good on the whole proof part.
你哥哥被绑架了吗
Your brother was abducted?
是啊
Yeah.
-我的天哪  -没事的
- Oh, my god. - It's fine.
我有充足的时间来适应
I mean, I've had time to adjust.
他是不是在你们小时候被绑走的
Did it -- did it happen when you were kids?
不是  大概就半小时之前
No. Like half an hour ago.
所以说你追捕飞碟都有三十年之久了
So, you've been hunting U.F.O.S for over three decades,
但你手头上却没有具体数据
and you basically have no concrete data
也没有可用的线索
and zero workable leads.
-这个...  -你知不知道
- Well, I   - Have you considered the possibility
你在追捕飞碟这一行  真不咋地
that you suck at hunting U.F.O.S?
我很乐意来帮忙
I'd like to help.
尽我所能
If I can.
迪恩
Dean!
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
这就是迪恩吗
Oh, that's Dean?
萨姆
Sam!
外星人把你哥哥送回来了诶
They brought your brother back.
好了
Okay.
没事的  萨姆
It's all right, Sam.
我理解  你得多陪陪你哥哥
I so totally understand you need time as a family.
可是...
But it's just...
它们到底什么样
What were they like?
它们个个都是牛逼闪闪又贪婪的二货
They were grabby, incandescent douchebags.
晚安
Good night.
-河蟹  -好吧
- Too soon.  - Okay.
你不开心了
Y-you're upset.
我被绑架了
I was abducted.
你却在和个"广罗香"瞎搞
And you were banging patchouli.
她没那么难闻吧
I didn't think she smelled that bad.
-我被外星人绑架了  - 我有去调查啊
- I was abducted by aliens!  - I was looking into it!
调查毛  我只不过消失了差不多一小时
Looking into it?! I was gone for like an hour!
-一小时  -大部分时间还浪费在走路上了
- An hour?  - And most of that was walking back to town!
迪恩  我猜你的表肯定停了
Dean, I think your watch is off.
你都失踪了一个晚上了
You've been gone all night.
你胡扯什么  我才没有
What are you talking about? No, I haven't.
凌晨四点吗
4:00 A.M.?
没错
Yeah.
飞碟可以穿越时空
U.F.O. Time-slip.
这和很多被绑故事里说的一样
That actually falls in line with a lot of abduction stories.
一样
"Falls in line"?
一样个毛
Nothing's falling in line!
来  喝一杯
Here. Drink.
-好  -谢谢
- Good. - Thank you.
现在  来
Now...Come on.
和我说说
Talk to me.
发生了什么
What happened?
是...这样
Well, uh...
有个...
There was this, uh...
天呐  萨姆
God help me, Sam,
有道很亮的白光
There was this bright white light.
没事的
It's okay.
这里很安全
Safe room.
就突然  我就
And then -- and suddenly, I was, uh...
我就到了另一个地方
I w-- I was in a different place.
那里有些  生物
And there were these...beings.
它们都太亮了  晃得我都不敢看
And they -- they were -- they were too bright to look at,
但我能感觉的到...
but I-I could feel them...
它们把我拉向一张桌子似的东西
pulling me towards this sort of...table.
-探测桌  -天哪  别说那么大声
- Probing table! - God, don't say that out loud!
好
Right.
你都做了些什么
Uh, so what did you do?
我就疯了
I went...crazy.
我开始到处乱踢
I started hacking and --
乱砍  开枪
and slashing and firing.
他们看起来有些惊讶
They -- they actually seemed surprised.
我想从来没人这样干过
I-I-I don't think anybody's ever done that before.
是啊
Yeah.
我和外星人亲密接触了一把  萨姆
I had a close encounter, Sam.
而且我赢了
And I won.
你应该去冲个澡
You should take a shower.
我是该去冲澡了
I should take a shower.
我要去  要去冲澡
I'm gonna -- I'm gonna take a shower.
所以  除了恶魔  天使
So, on top of all the demons and the angels
还有那些鬼魂和剥皮行者之外
and the ghosts and the skinwalkers,
原来还有...
it turns out that there's...
所以说  如果真有外星人
So, if aliens are actually real,
那接下来还会有什么
what's next, huh?
霍比特人
Hobbits?
我认真的
Seriously.
你刚刚给她使了个"怎么样"的眼色
You just gave her the silent "How you doin'."
什么
What?
我们对真实世界的认知正在被摧毁
Our reality's collapsing around us,
你居然还有心情勾搭女招待
and you're trying to pick up our waitress?!
你说得对
Yeah.
好吧  听着
Okay, look...
我有个问题
that brings up a question.
假设你有灵魂  你在调查一件案子
So, say you got a soul, and you're on a case,
然后你哥哥被外星人绑架了
and your brother gets abducted by aliens.
对  那你就要尽一切可能把他找回来
Yeah, then you do everything you can to get him back.
没错  你是尽力了
Right. You do.
但是  如果那天晚上基本没有线索呢
But what about when there are no more leads for the night?
我是说  如果你已经无能为力了
I mean, are you supposed to
那你就该
just sit there in the dark and suffer,
一个人孤坐在黑暗中忍受煎熬吗
even when there's nothing that can be done at that moment?
-没错  -什么
- Yes! - What?
没错
Yes.
你得孤坐在黑暗中  感受你失去了什么
You sit in the dark, and you -- you feel the loss.
确实
A-absolutely.
但是  我就不能一边做到你说的那些
But -- but couldn't I just do all that
一边和个嬉皮小妞发生关系么
and have sex with the hippie chick?
不行
No!
反正都是在黑暗中啊
It would be in the dark.
不  不行  因为你应该痛苦万分才对
No, you couldn't, because you would be suffering.
你不能一到晚上就把这事抛诸脑后了
And you can't just turn that off for the night.
谢了  伙计
Thanks, guys.
为啥不行
Why not?
因为如果你有灵魂的话
Because if you had a soul,
你的灵魂不会让你这么做
your soul wouldn't let you.
所以  你是说...
So, you're saying...
拥有灵魂等于忍受煎熬
Having a soul equals suffering.
没错  我就是这个意思
Yes, that's exactly what I'm saying.
就像...
Like...
你给莉莎打了无数个电话一样
the million times you almost called Lisa.
所以  你是说忍受煎熬是件好事
So, you're saying suffering is a good thing.
我是说  你没的选择
I'm saying it's the only game in town.
好吧
Okay.
所以  我们该怎么对付那些小绿人
So, how do we deal with the little green men?
从调查开始
Research.
我们要补习一个世纪的飞碟知识
We got about a century of UFO lore to catch up on,
可没有时间再...
and there's no time for --
那家伙怎么了
What's up with that guy?
哪个
Who?
窗户旁边那个
The guy by the window.
盯着我的那个
Giving me the stink eye.
你说那个条子
You mean the cop?
不  不是条子
No, not the cop.
那个家伙  就在
The guy! He's right --
现在不见了
Well, now he's gone.
谁不见了
Who's gone?
-咱赶紧走了行不  -你犯啥毛病
- Can we please just get out of here? - What's wrong with you?
-别逼我打你  -好吧
- Before I hit you. - Okay.
图书馆要关门了  我也差不多搞定了
Library's closing up soon. I'm almost done.
找着什么没有
You find anything?
是找得太多了
Yeah, way too much.
地球上几乎所有人都相信有飞碟
Everyone on the planet believes in UFOs,
所以他们会不停地写这方面的书
and they will not stop writing books about it.
好歹书上还是有标点符号的
Yeah, well, at least books have punctuation.
好吧  你接着查
All right, keep digging.
等你回来我们再研究你都找到了什么
We'll see what you got when you get back.
不是吧
Oh, no.
又来
Not again.
有乳头耶
Nipples?
你个小婊子
Bitch!
看什么
See what?
看什么  看这血迹
S-s-see what? See see t -- the -- the blood!
看看这里恶心得...
See all the -- the -- the blech!
不好意思  伙计  我啥也没看出来
Sorry, man. I'm not seeing it.
这么恶心你居然看不到  就在这儿
You don't see the -- the echh?! It's right there!
好吧  也就是说
Okay, let's go with
你看得到  但我看不到
you see it and I don't.
到底是啥玩意儿
What the hell was it?
是一个...
It was a...
一个迷你的...
a little...
裸女  行了吧
Naked lady, okay?
一个啥
It was a... a what?!
是一个迷你发光性感裸女  还带乳头的
It was -- it was a little, glowing, hot, naked lady with nipples.
而且
and...
她还打了我
and she hit me.
我现在不该笑  是吧
I'm not supposed to laugh, right?
好吧  当然  必须的
Right. Okay, sure.
话说...刚才那场暗夜惊魂的时候
Um...So, shot in the dark here,
你看到这位迷你裸女有翅膀吗
but did this...little lady have wings?
为啥这么问
What the hell made you say that?
她有  对不对
She did, didn't she?
是啊  但是你  你怎么
Yeah, but how -- how did you --
我查到的其中一个诡异的理论
One of the fringier theories I came across.
就和那个拿水晶的老疯婆唠叨的东西一样
I-it's actually what crazy crystal lady was yammering about.
如果这些绑架根本和飞碟无关呢
What if these abductions have nothing to do with UFOs?
-什么  -好吧  假设几个世纪以来
- What? - Okay, say these encounters
一直出现的这种状况
have been going on for centuries --
不是什么外星人造成的
not with extraterrestrials
而是由于某种地球以外的生物
but with ultra-terrestrials.
我是说  现在人们都管这叫
I mean, people nowadays say
什么外星人之类的
space aliens or whatever,
但是以前人们都管这叫...
but they used to call them...
-蓝精灵  -是小精灵
- Smurfs? - Fairies.
小精灵  拜托
Fairies? Come on.
迪恩  外星人和小精灵是有直接联系的
Dean, there's a straight line between ETs and fairies.
他们都会发光  都要绑架人类
Glowing lights, abductions.
这是不同包装下  同样的飞碟事件
I-it's all the same UFO stuff just under a different skin.
你真觉得飞碟的谜底就是
You seriously think the secret with the UFOs is --
明明是你把小仙女叮叮铃当披萨给烤了
Hey, you're the one who pizza-rolled tinker bell.
我只是帮你解释而已
I'm just doing the math.
但这也挺好的  起码是一条线索
But this is good. This is a lead.
什么线索
A lead where?!
小精灵
Fairies!
小仙女和小宝藏守护者  小幻形怪和小棕仙
Sprites and spriggans, boggarts and brownies.
这些小东西有很多名字
The little people have many names.
那是...
Well, that's, uh...
就是那个
That's her.
就是  就是这个迷你...
That's -- that's -- that's the little...
总之  我明白了这位小仙女叮叮铃就是小精灵
Anyway, I, uh, I-I get that tinker bells are fairies.
不过  那小小圣诞老人呢
But, uh, what about the tiny Santa Claus
还有巨魔  还有
and the troll and the --
那是花园矮人
Oh, oh, that's a garden gnome,
另外那个是大个儿地精
And that's a large goblin,
这些  这些都是小精灵吗
And that -- but they're all fairies?
没错
Yes.
小精灵们形态各异
Fairy comes in many shapes and sizes --
来自其他国度  会魔法又顽皮捣蛋的小东西
Magical, mischievous beings from the realm next door.
小精灵王国
The fairy realm?
就像那种其他维度的空间吗
So, it's like another dimension?
另一个世界  没错
Another reality, yes.
只有那些去到过那里又回到这个世界的人
Only people who have been there and returned to our world
能在这里看到小精灵
can see the fairy here.
好吧
Right.
小精灵为什么要绑架人类
Why are the fairies abducting people?
对此有很多种解释  但很少有接近事实的
Well, there is much theory and little fact.
我们知道他们只会抓走家里的大儿子
We know they only take first-born sons.
就像侏儒怪一样(德国传说)
Just like rumpelstiltskin did!
我觉得  他们可能被带到阿瓦隆
Personally, I think they're taken to Avalon
去服侍欧泊龙了
to service Oberon,
也就是精灵之王
king of the fairy.
迪恩
Dean...
你有没有
did you...
服侍过那个精灵之王欧泊龙
service Oberon, king of the fairies?
玛丽安
Marion...
如果真的有精灵
Let's say fairies are real, okay?
-我们能怎么做  -什么
- What can we do about them? - Sorry?
我是说  怎么
I mean, how can we...
和他们交流
Interact with them?
没错  没错
Yes, yes.
暴力的交流
Forcefully interact.
如果你们想找精灵帮忙
Well, if you want to win a fairy's favor,
就得送他们一碗新鲜奶油
leave a bowl of fresh cream.
他们爱死奶油了
They love cream.
这样
Okay.
有没有更暴力点的
Uh, and -- and more forcefully?
精灵都不喜欢铁器
Well, all fairy hate iron.
而黑暗精灵接会被银器灼伤
And the dark fairy burn when touched with silver.
还有什么
What else?
如果你在精灵面前撒上糖或盐
You could spill sugar or salt in front of them.
无论他们有多强大
No matter how powerful,
都必须弯腰去数颗粒
the fairy must stoop to count each grain.
这样啊
Well, all right.
这真是
That's -- wow.
太好玩了
Lot to absorb.
多谢了
Um, thank you.
先等等
Oh! Oh, stay!
把茶喝完
Finish your tea.
不得不说
I got to say,
我大爱这里的感觉
I-I-I love the feel.
就像  就像
It's, uh, it's -- it's...
就像袖珍版的亚利桑那州的赛多纳
It's like Sedona, Arizona, crapped in here.
总之极富质感
...Pewter-iffic is what it is.
真质感
Pewter-iffic.
你有大点的杯子吗
Do you have bigger cups?
天啊  我被附身了吗
God, is it on me?
-我感觉被那玩意附身了  -没有
- I feel like I've got the crazy on me. - No, you...
但你确实被精灵劫持过了
You did sit in some glitter, though.
还不如相信被飞碟劫持了
Just makes me want to believe in UFOs again.
我跟你说  你这些想法对行动可没帮助
Doesn't really give us a next move. I'll grant you that.
这种事应该打电话问鲍比
We can always put the call out to Bobby.
搞笑了吧
I'll be damned.
那不是那个钟表匠吗
Isn't that the watch guy?
爱死奶油哦
They love cream.
(布伦南钟表行)
你跟着他去酒吧
All right, you stick with half and half.
我去他店里看看
I'm gonna go check out his store.
不准勾引小妞
And no hippie chicks.
喂
Yeah.
这里到处都是精灵
Friggin' full of keeblers over here, man.
满屋子都是
Just full of 'em.
-什么  -就像故事里讲的
- What? - It's like -- it's like the story
修鞋匠养着一群精灵
with the -- with the shoe guy and all the elves.
你说布伦南会不会跟精灵
Hey, you -- you think Brennan made a deal
有什么交易
with a bunch of fairies?
等我电话
Let me get back to you.
好啊  布伦南先生
So, Mr. Brennan.
又见面了
Hello again.
别来烦我
Leave me alone.
我有说过你手工很好吗
Did I ever mention how beautiful your work is?
什么
What?
表做的极好极好
The watches -- just stunning.
但我很疑惑的是
But what I can't figure out
你一个人是怎么做出这么多表的
Is how one man can put out that much product.
我是说  别人不知道的话
I mean, hell, if I didn't know better,
还以为你有一群精灵帮你干活呢
I'd say you have a bunch of elves working for ya.
可惜我知道
Except I do know better.
你确实有一群精灵帮你干活
And you have a bunch of elves working for you.
神经病
You're insane.
那么  什么样的父亲会狠心用亲生儿子
So, tell me -- how does a father decide to trade his son
交换一堆钟表
for a bunch of watches?
我想你还是有灵魂的
I mean, I'm assuming you have a soul,
所以你到底是为了什么呢
so what's your excuse?
你不懂的
You don't understand.
根本不是这回事
It wasn't like that.
那是怎么回事
Then how was it?
我靠做这些钟表养家糊口三十年
I supported my family for 30 years making those watches.
这是我唯一会做的工作
It's the only thing I know how to do.
但得了帕金森症后
But the Parkinson's...
我无法控制住双手了
I was losing my hands.
我将失去一切
I was losing everything.
奶奶常说世上真的有精灵
My grandmother, she always used to say that they were real,
我小的时候她教过我
Told me all these stories when I was a kid
如何召唤精灵
about how to summon them,
如何得到精灵的帮助
how to get favors from them.
所以你会施咒语
So you learned how to work a spell.
我是说
I mean...
本来我都不知道行不行得通
Honestly, I doubted it would even work.
但我太绝望了
I was just desperate.
她留了一本书给我
She left me this book.
两个月前我就在店里进行了召唤
So I did the ceremony in my back office two months ago.
然后  出现了一个男人
And this...man appeared.
自称是小妖精
Said he was a leprechaun.
小妖精
A leprechaun?
我请求他治好我的病
I asked him just to cure my hands,
但他说他可以做得更好
but he said he would do even better.
他可以帮我达到前所未有的高度
He'd make me more successful than I'd ever been.
说可以送我几个工人
He told me he'd bring a crew of workers,
以挽救我的事业和名声
that I could save my business, save my name.
条件是
In exchange for...?
条件是给他们提供休息住所
He just wanted a place for them to rest,
以享受这片沃土的滋润
"To take of the fruit and fat of the land."
我
I...
我就同意了
I said yes.
都没多想
I-I wasn't thinking.
沃土的滋润是指
And the "Fruit and the fat" Was...
我的大儿子
My first-born.
不光是我的
But not just mine.
还有其他人的
There's been others.
但他们贪婪不已
They're not stopping.
根本不打算收手
They're not going to stop.
肯定有法子破除咒语
There's got to be a way to reverse the spell.
有的
There is.
但那本书
But the book is...
放在我店里保险柜里
It's in the safe in my shop.
他们根本不让我靠近
They won't let me near it.
这就像是一场噩梦
It's been a nightmare.
你能看得见精灵
So you can see the fairies?
没错
Yes.
-救命  -抓到了
- Help! - I got you!
抓到你了  你个小精灵
I got you, you little fairy!
你们精灵有什么阴谋
What do you want, you fairy?
-我要杀光你们精灵  -救命
- I'll kill you, you fairy! - Help!
说啊  精灵
Talk, fairy!
老爸
Daddy!
天啊  悲剧了
Oh, god, no.
我闹着玩的
I'm just kidding.
现在  别担心  布伦南
All right, now, don't worry, Brennan.
我们能做到的
We can do this.
你破除咒语的时候
Just, uh, my brother and I are gonna cover you
我和我哥会保护你  好吗
While you reverse the ritual, all right?
迪恩  怎么回事
Dean! Hey, dude! What happened?!
萨姆
Sam!
Sam! Hey!
我该咋办啊
What am I supposed to do?!
收拾那些精灵
Fight the fairies!
你去收拾那些精灵
You fight those fairies!
收拾了他们
Fight the fairies!
我只是想问问
I'm just trying to understand...
你到底是为啥要进行这种仇恨犯罪
Exactly what kind of hate crime this even was.
那不是仇恨犯罪
It wasn't a hate crime.
如果那位先生是个彻彻底底的同性恋
I mean, if this gentlemen were a full-sized homosexual,
你觉得
Would that, uh,
你觉得能接受吗
Would that be okay with you?
我不仇恨任何人
I don't hate any-size person
或是  任何  同性恋
Or -- or -- or any-size gay guy.
他不是同性恋  哪有那么巧
Well, he's not gay, as it happens.
但他是蒂普顿县的地方检察官
But he is the district attorney for tipton county.
非常严厉的人哦
Runs a tight ship, tell you what.
很高兴听说他这么兢兢业业
Well, it's nice to hear he's done so well for himself,
毕竟现在
Considering his, uh
毕竟现在...经济不景气啊
...Considering the tough economic times.
真有他的
Good for him.
小子
Son...
你毁了
...You are all kinds of messed up.
他们在吗
Are they here?
在  但没关系
Yeah, but it's all right.
奶油把它们都放倒了  就像龙舌兰酒
Cream hits them like tequila.
[咒语]
你
You.
你就是那妖精
You're the leprechaun?
没错  就是我
Indeed I am.
抱歉弄脏了
Sorry about the mess,
但你朋友
But your friend here, uh...
完成他的交易了
Went back on his deal.
可你没跟他说清楚交易筹码
Well, you weren't very clear with him on the terms.
我告诉过他  会有代价的
I told him there was a price.
我们一旦来了
Once we come,
就再也不走了
We come to stay.
你们抓走了大儿子  然后呢
So you take first-borns, and then what?
你就在一旁看着
You just sit back and watch
他们用一堆飞碟之类的废话
While they cover up the abductions for you
帮你掩盖绑架的事实
With all that crazy U.F.O. Crap?
当然  都是你怂恿的
Which you help encourage, naturally.
完美的骗局
Nice con.
可惜你的骗局被揭穿了  韦恩
But your cover's blown now, Wayne.
揭穿  被谁
"Blown"? To whom?
布伦南已经死了
Brennan's dead.
你哥哥
Your brother?
他去过我们的地盘
He's marked.
已经被做了标记
Been to the ranch.
他现在是我们的了
He's ours now.
那好
Yeah, well...
还有我呢
Then there's me.
你
You?
我想让你看见我的时候
But you can only see me...
你才能看见我
If I let you.
确实
True.
但你终究得靠近我
But you'll have to get near me eventually.
而我反应很快的
And I have very good reflexes.
你和他们不一样  是不是
You're not like the rest of them, are you?
没有
Nope.
不  我能感觉到
No. I could see that right off.
你缺了一样东西
You're missing a certain piece,
在中心那里  是不是
Right in the center, ain't ya?
谁说的
Says who?
我们精灵对能量最为敏感
Oh, we fairy folk are all about energy.
人类的灵魂有一种特殊的
And the human soul gives off a certain
香味
Perfume.
你的灵魂很遥远
Your soul is far away,
但并非遥不可及
But not completely out of reach.
是么
That so?
萨姆
Sam...
我可以帮你拿回来
I can get it back for you.
但要做个交易
for a price.
听起来不错
That's adorable.
它被锁在一个恶魔的盒子里
It's locked in a box with the devil.
对你们来说是恶魔  对我们来说不是
Your devil, not mine.
天使都做不到的事
There's no freakin' way
妖精是不可能做到的
A leprechaun can do what angels cannot.
天使  算了吧
Angels. Oh, please.
我在说真正的魔法  孩子
I'm talking about real magic, sonny,
从我族这边
From my side of the fence.
找到一条密径
Got a way of gettin' in back doors.
这么说来  你是我的蓝精灵了
So you're my blue fairy?
你可以把我变回完整的人
You can make me a real boy again?
只要你许个愿
When you wish upon a star.
好
Yeah.
我有个愿望
I got a wish.
铁
Iron.
很疼
Painful...
但不是什么大问题
But not a deal breaker.
算了吧  小伙子
Come on, lad.
你已经打过最有把握的一枪了
You've already taken your best shot.
对
You're right.
我不开枪了
I'm done shooting.
帮我个忙
So do me a favor...
数这个
And count this.
不
Oh, no.
我咋不早这么干呢
why didn't I do that earlier?
一
1...
三
...3...
可恶
You ass!
四  五
...4...5.
混账
Damn it!
[咒语]
那么
So...
敬那个迷你的地方检察官
Here's to the tiniest D.A.
感谢他撤销了控诉
Thanks for dropping the charges.
人小权大啊
Little big man.
我很好奇
I was wondering something.
什么
Yeah?
他们那些魔法真的能找回
You think lucky charms really could have, you know,
你的灵魂吗
Returned soul to sender?
得了吧
come on.
根本想都别想
It's crazy to think.
不过他说得挺像那么回事的
He did talk a good game, though.
但你拒绝了
You said no.
为什么
Why?
那是个交易
It was a deal.
交易从来都没有好结果
When's a deal ever been a good thing?
我只是想知道他有什么办法
I'm just trying to figure out how it works in there.
伙计  我的脑子还在呢
Dude, I-I do still have all my brain cells.
要说有什么区别的话  我脑子现在更好使了
If anything, my brain works better now.
我只是想确定下你的想法
I'm just making sure that's where your head's at.
确定下你是否犹豫过
You know, that you're not having second thoughts
要拿回你的灵魂
About getting your soul back.
你没犹豫吧
You're not, are you?
没有
No.